

Sam Ayres **Director of Technology**

Contact

hello@5am.dev

Brooklyn, New York

Education

Batchelors: Web Design

University of the West of England, 2011 - 2014

Socials

GitHub

StackOverflow

LinkedIn

Portfolio

Languages & Frameworks

HTML CSS PHP React

MJML

Infrastructure / Hosting / DB

Git SQL MongoDB

Wordpress CiviCRM Drupal

Storyblok GrapesJS Heroku

Mautic Apache NGINX

Design

XD Figma Photoshop Sketch

SUMMARY

I am a motivated web development professional with ten years of experience. I am dedicated to making a positive impact on both the projects I work on and the people I work with. I measure success by meeting business goals and ensuring client satisfaction. I help create value by delivering large-scale projects through innovation and streamlined processes.

EXPERIENCE

CultHealth, New York, United States

Director of Technology, Oct 2022 - Present Associate Director of Technology, Jul 2021 - Oct 2022

My responsibilities include building out the entire department. I facilitated all processes, technologies, timelines, and hiring.

My first focus was to establish a solid foundation for how we work. This involved implementing appropriate DevOps solutions, including a Git workflow, designating approved frameworks, and creating Kanban boards and Gantt charts.

To improve quality control, I put in place a thorough QA process to help reduce mistakes. This included the use of custom compilers, testing suites, and checklists.

l also worked towards automating everyday processes to speed up development time. This included automating tasks such as:

- Banner generation tool leveraging Gulp and Mustache.
- Email generation tool leveraging Gulp and MJML.
- Screenshots of banners, emails and websites to enable a more efficient department reviewal process.
- Uploading banners, emails and websites to staging server upon completion.
- Sending preview emails via the SendGrid API to emailonacid test suite.

Heartbeat, New York, United States

Senior Web Developer, Mar 2020 - Jun 2021

Freelance Senior Web Developer, Feb 2020 - Mar 2020

As the lead developer for large ongoing client projects spanning several websites, I worked with many team departments to help meet strict client deadlines. My contributions and responsibilities included:

- Creating a rapid website prototyping tool.
- Replacing vanilla JS projects with progressive React applications.
- Leveraging React state logic to reduce user errors and ensure successful workflows.
- Porting and refactoring out-of-date Drupal modules to Symfony services.

Circle Interactive, Bristol, United Kingdom

Web Developer, Feb 2016 - Jul 2019

Circle Interactive was my introduction to multi-client working. I enjoyed the opportunity to use new technologies, such as React. During my time there, I:

- Introduced a Git workflow for the development team.
- Implemented an automated repository creation service using Drupal custom modules.
- Led a project for a React-based rental web application.
- Mentored students and helped them develop their abilities in web development.